Chamberlain, Neil W. Papers 6233
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Neil W. Chamberlain Papers
1934-2003
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Chamberlain, Neil W.
6233
5 cubic feet
5 linear ft.
Papers, publications.
This collection consists of four series: professional correspondence, personal correspondence, professional publications: articles, professional publications: monographs, professional publications: reviews, other writing: fiction, other writing: poetry.
6388747
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
D. Mordente, March 04, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 04, 2016
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of four series: professional correspondence, personal correspondence, professional publications: articles, professional publications: monographs, professional publications: reviews, other writing: fiction, other writing: poetry.
Some of the publications with issues included in this collection: Industrial & Labor Relations Review, The Right to Work, Labour Education in the British Caribbean, Daedalus Perspectives on Business, The Journal of Human Resources, Labour Gazette, Symposium, Management in the XXI Century, The Hermes Exchange, The Columbia Journal of World Business, Business Horizons, Columbia Law Review, Industrial News Letter, The Journal of Political Economy, Brooklyn Law Review, The Accounting Review, Business & Society Review, Monthly Labor Review, Industrial & Labor Relations Review.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Arbitration, Industrial--United States.; Collective bargaining--United States.; Industrial relations -- United States; Chamberlain, Neil W.
6388747
- Jehovah & Prophets: Part of Manuscript (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  p.40-80
- The Case for a New Democratic Revolution (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Revisions of "Jehovah at the Cedars of Lebanon" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  (revisions in writing)
- The Old Lady (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Neil W. Chamberlain: A Retrospective Analysis of His Scholarly Work and Influence (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Falconry (Box 1, Folder 6)
- David (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The Days of Frenzied Finance (Box 1, Folder 8)
- US Dept. of Labor Certificate of Appreciation (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Academy of Management Special Citation to Neil W. Chamberlain (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Yugoslavia Tickets & Passport 1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- People's Penny Weekly (Box 1, Folder 12)
- N.W. Chamberlain Journal (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Honorary Yale degree (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Box of notes (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Industrial & Labor Relations Review, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  v.10:no.1 (1956:Oct.)
- The Right to Work Issue, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  v.27:no.1 (1954:May)
- Daedalus Perspectives on Business, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Winter 1969
- Speeding Up & Smoothing Economic Growth, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Hearings Before the Joint Economic Committee Congress of the US 1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Labour Education in the British Caribbean, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- The Journal of Human Resources, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 7A)
  v.1:no.1 (1966:Summer)
- Labour Gazette, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  v.48:no.11 (1969:July)
- Columbia Journal of Law & Social Problems 14th Annual Columbia Law Symposium, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  v.10:no.1 (1973:Fall)
- Management in the XXI Century, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Nov. 12-14, 1979
- Challenge Magazine: Organized Labor- A Diminishing Force?, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  January issue
- Business Philosophy (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Personal & Professional (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Business Leadership (Box 2, Folder 14)
- NYC 1886 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Hallam's Harvest (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Pentland Press Inc. Reader's Report (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Fiscal & Monetary Policy- 1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Nov.14-15
- Automation Risiko und Chance Band II (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Employment & Unemployment: The Problems of the 1960's, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Association for Comparative Economics: Proceedings of the Natl. Assoc. for Comparative Economics Meetings-1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Nov. 27-29
- The Hermes Exchange, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Oct. 1968
- International Management (Box 3, Folder 6)
- The Columbia Journal of World Business Issue, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Winter 1978
- Columbia University Folder, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Challenge: The Magazine of Economic Affairs Issue, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Jun. 1964
- Challenge: The Magazine of Economic Affairs Issue, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Oct. 1960
- Business Horizons, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  v.3:no.2 (1960:Summer)
- Public Relations Journal: The American Economy, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Nov. 1975
- Apsirationen in der Wirtschaftsanalyse (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Preliminary Study of Labor Relations in the Tugboat Industry (Box 3, Folder 14)
- The Union's Role in Production Management (Box 3, Folder 15)
- The Nature of the Collective Bargaining Agreement (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Columbia Law Review, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  v.48:no.6 (1948:Sep.)
- Industrial News Letter, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  v.9:no.4 (1947:June)
- Labor & Management Center: Functional Roles of Union & Management, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Union Obligations Under the National Labor Relations Act (Box 3, Folder 20)
- The Journal of Political Economy, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  v.52:no.2 (1944:June)
- The Nature & Scope of Collective Bargaining (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Brooklyn Law Review, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  v.10:no.2 (1940:Dec.)
- Professor Hanson Fiscal Policy and the Debt (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Collective Bargaining in the Public Sector (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Columbia Journal of World Business (Box 3, Folder 26)
- The Accounting Review, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  Oct. 1962
- Business & Society Review, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  Winter 1974-1975
- Monthly Labor Review, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  v.90:no.4 (1967:Apr.)
- The Challenge: The Magazine of Economic Affairs, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  July/Aug. 1966
- The Challenge: The Magazine of Economic Affairs, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  Jan/Feb. 1966
- "Reviews About" folder (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Atlantic Monthly, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  v.217:no.1 (1966:Jan.)
- Atlantic Monthly, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  v.215:no.6 (1965:June)
- Atlantic Monthly, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  v.214:no.3 (1964:Sep.)
- Atlantic Monthly, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  v.214:no.1 (1964:July)
- Public Responsibilities of Private Industry, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Industrial & Labor Relations Review, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  v.16:no.2 (1963:Jan.)
- Industrial Relations: A Journal of Economy & Society, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  v.4:no.1 (1964:Oct.)
- Intellectual Odyssey folder (Box 3, Folder 40)
- "Baghdad" folder (Box 3, Folder 41)
- "David" folder (Box 3, Folder 42)
- "Hallam's Harvest" folder (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Autistry (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Figures in a Revolution (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Envelope from the Ohio University Press (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Resume Submission to the Carole Abel Literary Agency (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Envelope to Ms. Harriet Fergenbaum (with "Hallam's Harvest" submission) (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Envelope with copy of "Hallam's Harvest", 1961 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Challenge Magazine (Box 3, Folder 50)
  March
- Book Shelf Scrapbook & Album (Box 4, Folder 1)
- 1886 Election folder (Box 4, Folder 2)
- "Byron Bunyan's Progress" (Box 4, Folder 3)
  two copies in envelope
- Poetry, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- "Baghdad" revised final (Box 4, Folder 5)
- NYU envelope (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Poetry envelope (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Various Poetry- Professor Werner (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Professional folder (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Correspondence with Robert Black envelope (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Salzburg Seminar, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Rachmanioff's Poetry (Box 4, Folder 12)
- The Place of Business in America's Future (Box 4, Folder 13)
- APR envelope (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Correspondences Re: Armand Erpf Professorship (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Reviews of "Intellectual Odyssey" (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Smith & Bentham, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  April 1979.
- Report of Visit to Indonesia & PPG for ICA, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Poetry envelope from Sutcliffe Studio, Inc. (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Envelope from The Brookings Institution (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Letter to Arthur Goldberg on Vietnam War (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Time & Place in Eco Theory- University of Hartford seminars, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- From Now to Hallelujah (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Envelope from Nathaniel Field, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Frenzied Finance (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Byron Bunyan's Progress (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Jehovah (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Materials (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Materials Cont.d- Mixed Ideas (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Envelope from Williams (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Theory as Fiction (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Pentland Press (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Publishing (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Publishing 2 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Hall am (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Hallam's Harvest (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Byron Bunyan's Progress (Box 5, Folder 2)
- For Labor and Henry George: The New York City Mayoralty Campaign of 1886 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Intellectual Odyssey donation (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Who's Who in America Certificate of Recognition, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Figures in a Revolution or The Men Who Brought Forth a New Nation (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Columbia Recognition (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Business Cycle 1957 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Business Cycle 1955 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- The Rising Sun 1937 Nihon (Box 5, Folder 10)
- IRAA Recognition: Life Achievment Award, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Neil W. Chamberlain: A Retrospective Analysis of His Scholarly Work and Influence reprints (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Labor Education Conference in Jamaica (Box 5, Folder 13)
- People's Penny Weekly, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  v.1:no.1 (1934:Sep.)
- Walking Through the Year- envelope from Robert B. Haynes (Box 5, Folder 15)